Now that the rainy season has started, it rains quite a lot.
梅雨に入り
雨の日が多くなった
梅雨は好きじゃない
I don't like the rainy season.
As the humidity rises, so does my misery.
高まる湿度に冷えして
不快指数も増していく
I'm Tachibana Chizuru!
橘千鶴です
My best feature is the mole under my eye!
チャームポイントは泣きぼくろでーす
I'm Asaba Yuuta.
浅羽悠太です
双子の弟がいます
I have a younger twin brother.
You're identical!
よ　そっくり
I'm Matsuoka Shun.
松岡春です
え-と　茶道部に入っています
Let's see... I'm in the tea club.
Shun-chan, you're so cute!
きゃー　春ちゃん可愛い
What?
I'm Satou Masaki.
佐藤茉咲　高校一年生
I'm a first year.
Finally, a girl!
待ってました　女の子
は　まさかお前も男ってことは
Don't tell me you're a boy, too?
Asaba Yuuki.
浅羽祐希　愛読書はanimenja
My favorite magazine is Animaga.
Yeah! It's cool!
yeah　It’s cool
抑えきれない鼓動　どこにいたって　分かってしまう
早已知道这无法压抑的鼓动源于何处
Time for the final introduction.
はい　では最後の一人
張り切ってどうぞ
The floor is yours!
こら　要チ　波を止めるな
Hey, Kanamecchi! Don't stop the flow.
溢れ出した焦燥感　いつから恋って気付いていた
不知何时发觉这溢出的焦躁感是基情
You have to introduce yourself at a mixer.
合コンの基本は自己紹介だぞ
And recently, more things that contribute to my misery have sprung up around me.
そして最近俺の周りにはさらに不快指数の存在が増えた
やり直したい　昨日がフラグだっていうなら
如果说欲再次上演的昨日是伏笔的话
毎日何度でも　重ねたいよ
每天无论多少次都想重演
yappari kimi da yo ne
Oh hey, it's you?
たとえもし君が　世界の果てにいても　今すぐに見つけるから
假如你在世界尽头 我也能立马找到你
honto odoroita yo
You startled me
futari yoku aruita namikidoori
Here we are, on the tree-lined road we walked so often
otona ni naru no wo
I couldn't wait to grow up, and kept you at a distance, didn't I?
mattezu ni toozaketeita no wa atashi datta ne
itsumo
As always,
mainasu ichido no ame ga furu
the icy rain falls
kimi ga kureta namida
comprised of tears you cried for me
sono yasashisa made wakaranakute
That kindness I didn't understand
zutto kono mune wo shimetsuketa
lay heavy on my heart all the time
mainasu ichido no ame ga furu
The icy rain falls
tsumetasugiru namida
comprised of tears unbearably cold
hagurakasu taido ni okotteta kedo
Although I was angry at my evasive personality
jitsu wa sukuwareteita n da ne
you cured me of that, didn't you
Come on, hurry. Come on!
Why are we doing a mixer?
I'm only here because you insisted that I should come.
You're no fun.
I even had Yukki and Shun-chan pretend to be girls to even up the numbers.
I don't understand why you did that.
Now, now, now, forget about this shy boy.
Okay.
What kind of guy do you like?
How about it, Yukki?
Let's see...
I suppose someone who could prove to me...
that there are things more important than money.
I'll do it! I'll prove it to you!
I'll even embrace everything in your past!
I promise I'll do it!
What about you, Shun-san?
U-Um, someone kind, I guess.
You'll fall in l-love with someone as long as they're nice?
Hey, Kanamecchi, what's your type?
I dunno.
This guy's into older women.
Much older women.
No way! You like mature women?
No!
Yuuki-Mama, Kanamecchi's going to hurt me!
All men are like that.
They never show any kindness.
Yuuki-Mama!
What are you guys doing?
And why are we having this mixer?
Youth is all about having mixers!
What?
Young people must never forget about mixers!
But you've forgotten that this group isn't right for mixers.
Also, there's the weather.
The weather?
Huh?
Uh oh.
You monkey!
Damn that monkey.
Oh, Tsukahara-kun.
I'm done here. It's all yours.
I'm amazed you were at an outdoor party in this weather.
There was nothing amazing about it.
Aside from Tachibana-kun,
you're all childhood friends, aren't you?
橘君以外は皆幼馴染だっけ
Yes, since kindergarten.
ほう　まあ　一応幼稚園から
I see.
えー　じゃあ　そのごとに比べると皆変わったでしょう
I'm sure you've all changed a lot since then.
全員あのままです
We haven't changed one bit.
Shun's always been a flowery guy,
春は昔から花飛ばしてたし
and Yuuta and Yuuki were even more problematic as little kids.
悠太と祐希は今以上に質悪い
They really were a couple of precocious preschoolers.
ませた幼稚園児だし
でもそうなんだよね
You're right.
子供って大人が思っている以上にませてて
Children are always more precocious than adults think.
俺が高校の職場体験で幼稚園に行った時も大変だったな
While I was working in high school, I visited a kindergarten, and the children there were a handful.
Now that you mention it, I guess I was pretty mature for my age, too.
確かに俺も　ませてたかっ言われれば
Kaori-sensei!
香先生
Yes, yes.
Kaname-kun, what's wrong?
要君どうしたんですか
I've figured it out.
俺は分かってしまったんだ
どんなに雪が降り積もろうとも
No matter how much it snows,
the flowers of love will always bloom.
恋の花が咲き乱れる春はやってくるんだよ
なんか　要君くさいよ
Kaname-kun, you reek of cheesiness.
That's not what that means!
そういうくさいじゃねえだろう
穂稀高校の兄さんたちが職場体験で来てくれました
The students from Homare High School are here to help us work.
今日一日皆の先生になってくれます
They'll be your teachers for the day.
This is Kouichi-sensei and Akira-sensei.
晃一先生と明先生です
Nice to meet you.
よろしく
Nice to meet you!
はい　よろしく
Um, what should we do?
あのう　俺たちは何をすれば
You can start by reading them picture books.
じゃあ　まずは絵本を読んであげてください
Who does he think he is...
talking to my Kaori-sensei like that?
何だよ　あいつ
いきなり俺の香先生と親しげに話しあがって
恋って果かないよね
Love is fleeting.
It's not over yet!
まだ終わってねえよ
I'll never lose to a guy like that!
あんな男に俺が負けるはずがない
This brings back memories.
懐かしいな
When I was your age, I cried when I read this.
お兄ちゃんね　君たちぐらいの時これ読んで泣いちゃったんだ
白雪姫かわいそうって
I felt so bad for Snow White.
Did you really?
本当ですか
Yeah. I was a crybaby.
うん　泣き虫だったから
ダっサいの　泣いてお姫様が守れるのかよ
How lame.
How can you protect the princess when you're crying?
俺はそんなことになる前に　魔女と戦ってやるよ
I'd fight the witch before anything happened to her!
すみません　この子お金ですべて解決できると思ってるんで
I'm sorry.
He believes he can solve any problem with money.
武力で
No, with strength!
Onii-chan, look, look!
お兄ちゃん　見て見て
Look at mine first!
私のが先に見てもらうの
Oh, um...
Yours is terrible.
No, yours is.
Don't fight...
あのう　喧嘩は
Your rival's popular.
モテモテだね　君のライバル
He thinks he's so great because he's sorta tall and handsome.
ちょっと背が高くて顔いいほうだからって調子に乗ってんだよ
俺のが全然
I'm way better.
うん　あの兄さんの格好よさなんて要君と比べたら勝るともぉとらないよ
Yeah.
Compared to your good looks,
his good looks don't seem inferior at all.
That means I'm worse than him!
それじゃ俺負けてんだろう
It's okay, Kaname-kun.
大丈夫ですよ　要君
There are always obstacles in love.
恋には生涯がつきものです
初恋は実らないっていうんじゃないですか
They say your first love never works out.
You're not helping!
ほら　手伝ってねんだろう
Hooray! A snowball fight!
わー　雪合戦
Now you've done it!
やったな　待って
Get back here!
ああ　一人で平気
Are you okay by yourself?
Does he...
何か　俺
He hates you!
嫌われてるね
He does.
はい　ですね
大丈夫だ　だって俺のが香先生のこと好きだもん
It's okay.
I love Kaori-sensei.
お　要君　大きいね
Kaname-kun, that's huge.
Why don't we combine yours with mine and make a snowman?
そうだ　先生のと合体させて　雪だるまにしようか
I'll stack them.
じゃあ　先生が乗せるね
Kaori-se—
香せん
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか
S-Sorry.
す..すみません
Don't worry about it.
いいえ
There you go.
よし　っと
できたよ　雪だるま
Your snowman's complete.
Are you okay?
大丈夫？
I don't need your pity.
お前なんかに心配されたくねえよ　バーカ
Jerk!
Um, did I do something?
あのう　俺何か
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いすんなよ
I could've helped Kaori-sensei, too.
俺だって香先生を助けられたんだからな
What? What is this?
何だよ　何だよこれ　超格好悪い
I look like such an idiot.
格好いいよね
You're a cool little guy.
Snow White
俺は泣いてただけだったよ
I could only cry, but you're different.
でも君は違うんだもんね
You can fight for her and defend her.
戦って守ってあげるんだもんね
格好いいよ
You're a cool little guy.
Damn it.
くそう　なれたらいい
I hope...
自分もいつか
Someday, I hope...
I can be just like him.
この人みたいになれたら
How embarrassing.
はっつ　いくら子供のころの話とは言え
I know I was just a kid, but...
あ　くそう　顔が熱い
Damn it. My face is burning.
Huh?
あれ
Is something wrong?
どうかした
No, it's nothing.
いや　なんでもないです　失礼します
If you'll excuse me...
I wonder how those kids are doing.
あの時の子たち　元気かな
You And I
Damn.
くそう　あの子ザルが合コンとかわけわからねこと言い出すから
It's that stupid monkey's fault...
He made us have that stupid mixer.
It's really pouring.
よく降る
He's a surprisingly deep sleeper.
意外と起きないもんだね
He's defenseless.
無防備すぎでしょう　この人
You shouldn't do that.
ちょっと　みんな　ダメですよ
Now, now.
Oh. Kaname, you're looking well.
なんだ　要元気そうだね
なんでいんだよ　おめえら
What are you doing here?
あのう　お見舞いに
We came to visit.
Visit?
お見舞い？
もう　季節の変わり目に風邪拗らせちゃうなんて
I can't believe you caught a cold as soon as the season changed.
Kanamecchi, you're like an old man.
要チおじいちゃんみたい
Whose fault is it I caught this cold?
誰のせいで風邪引いたんだよ
Ow. You're mean!
痛い　ひどい　おじいちゃんのためにわざわざお見舞いに来たのに
And we came all the way here to visit you, old man!
Who are you calling an "old man"?
誰がおじい
Kaname-kun, are you okay?
要君　大丈夫ですか
I'm fine.
平気だって
Mail received
Asaba Yuuki
Yuuki!
祐希
Why are you taking pictures of me?
てめ　何シャメ撮ってんだよ
消せよ　俺携帯寄越せ
Delete that!
Come on! Give me your phone!
Give you my phone?
携帯寄越せ？
個人情報たっぷりの俺の携帯か
You think I'd give you my phone when it has all sorts of personal information on it?
What?
Personal information about the top student in our grade... doesn't come cheap.
学年トップの俺の個人情報は　高いぞ
ははは　似てねぇ　似てねぇけど　いいよ　祐キーの要君
That's nothing like him!
It's nothing like him,
but I like your Kanamecchi impression!
What's good about it?
どこがだ
っつか　お前も声を殺して笑ってんじゃねえ
Don't you laugh under your breath at me!
ごめんなさい
似てねえ
Sorry.
Enough.
もういい　お前らは力使い
I'll force you to...
No, you have to rest.
ダメですよ　ちゃんと寝てないと
Let go, Shun!
放せ　春　あいつがいる限り
I can't rest peacefully as long as they're here!
俺ニャンみわねぇ
Hey, do these look good on me?
ねね　似合う
Yeah, but if you wear them too long, you'll damage your eyes.
似合うけど　あんましてると　視力落ちるよ
Your house sure is nice, Kanamecchi.
つーか　いいとこ住んでるな　要チ
皆要君のためにわざわざありがとうね
Thank you for going out of your way to come visit Kaname-kun.
Oh, thank you.
あ　すいません
あら　こちら初めましてね
I haven't seen you before.
どうも　要君のお母さんです
Nice to meet you. I'm Kaname-kun's mother.
橘千鶴です
I'm Tachibana Chizuru.
You're quite young... And beautiful!
お母様若いっすね　そしてきれいっす
あらあら　嬉しい
Why, thank you.
Kaname-kun, he just made a pass at me.
要君　お母さんほどかれちゃた　焼き餅焼く
Are you jealous?
別に
Not really.
Hey, you shouldn't make a woman cry!
おなこ泣かすな
Why is she crying, anyway?
何で泣くんだよ
Huh? There's one extra juice.
あれ　ジュースが一つ多いですね
あ　あたしの
Oh, that's mine.
You're gonna drink in here, too?
飲むのかよ　ここで
Because I want to talk to you, Kaname-kun.
だってだって　お母さんも要君とお話がしたいもの
You can talk to me any time.
いつでもできるじゃん
Liar.
うそ　要君そっけないじゃない　手だって最近繋いでくれないし
You're always so stoic.
You've even stopped holding my hand recently.
何年も前から繋いでない場合　最近は不適当です
I haven't held your hand in years.
I wouldn't call that recent.
ね　そんなにうぜー　お母さんのことそんなにうぜーの
Do I annoy you?
Do I really annoy you so much?
何そのうぜーって
What's with "annoying me"?
そういうんじゃなくてさ　時の流れっていうか
That's not it. As time goes on, it just—
あんなに
But you said... But you said that you loved me!
あんなに好きだって言ってくれたのに
もうあのごろの二人には戻れないの
Can't we go back to the way we used to be?
何もかも嘘すぎるの
Is it too late?
Hey!
ちょっと
Has the love disappeared?
愛は消えてしまうの
That's not something you should say to your son!
息子に使うセリフじゃないから　それ
思い出しなよ　最初で最後の女だと誓ったあの日を
You have to remember the day...
that you told her she'd be your first and last.
That never happened!
どんな日だ　親子だっつうの
We're family!
あ　スーパーに行ってこなくちゃ
I need to go to the supermarket!
Oh, Hisa-chan!
あら　日紗ちゃん
Oh, hello.
おばさん　こんにちは
こんにちは
Hello.
Your mom's pretty cute, Kanamecchi.
なんか可愛いな　要チのお母さん
I try to avoid introducing her to my friends.
あんまり知り合いに紹介したくねえけどな
要君　ちょっと横になった方が
Kaname-kun, you should lie down.
I'm fine.
大丈夫だよ
そうだ　今日休んだ分の授業を大丈夫ですか
Oh, right. Will you be able to do make-up work for the classes you missed today?
祐希君たちにノートを取っても
I had Yuuki-kun and Chizuru-kun take notes for—
I'll be fine.
いいよ
I'm sure they didn't take notes anyway.
どうせいノート取ってねえし　あいつら
Then, I'll...
じゃ　僕が教え
I said I'll be fine.
いいっつってんだろう
I see. You're right.
そうですか　ですね
いや　今やってるとこは暗記系だから　困ってない
I just have to memorize the stuff...
that we're doing right now, so it'll be fine.
要
Kaname.
あんた風邪引いたんだって
I heard you caught a cold.
Ah, Hisako-chan.
あ　日紗子ちゃん
Shun-kun, it's good to see you again!
春君　久しぶり
あ　また髪の毛伸びてる
You grew your hair out again.
要チの部屋に女が押しかけてきた
A girl barged into Kanamecchi's room!
Who is she? Is she your girlfriend?
何々　彼女？
How naughty!
いやー　不潔
Stop saying nasty stuff.
気色悪いこと言うな
She's just a childhood friend.
ただの幼馴染だよ
誰がこんな怪力女
Who'd date this brute?
Nice to meet you. I'm Aida Hisako.
あら　初めまして　相田日紗子です
Same here. I'm Tachibana Chizuru.
どうもっす　橘千鶴っす
いてな　病人殴るなよ
Ow! You shouldn't punch sick people!
Then you should shut up and rest like a sick person.
あんたこそ　病人らしく黙って寝てなさいよ
お　なんだこれ
What's this?
要チの机の引き出しから写真　発見
I found a photo in your desk drawer.
おい　勝手に机いじんなよ
Hey, don't touch my desk!
見て
Let me see, let me see!
見せて見せて
ほ　これはこれは
What do we have here?
おえ
Hey!
Isn't this from that time your family and mine...
これあれじゃない
私んちと要んちでバービキューだったかな　した時の
had that... I think it was a barbecue...
Is it really?
Math II
そうなの
That's all?
なんだ　もっと奇想天外なのを期待したのに　あーあ
I was hoping for something more unexpected.
Math II
English II
本当　要の机の上って勉強道具しか置いてないもんね
You don't have anything but study materials on your desk.
English II
Your disappointment is making me angry.
勝手にがっかりされても腹立つがな
Who's this?
この人誰
私のお姉ちゃん　靜奈っていうの
That's my sister. Her name's Shizuna.
ふん
Enough already!
もういいだろう
I still can't believe you'd treasure a photo like that.
でも似合わねぇ　要チが大事に写真保管するなんて
That's not it.
違うっつうの
I stuck it in there because I didn't have anywhere else to keep it.
しまう場所がなくて適当に突っ込んだだけだよ
Really?
本当？
Shut up. Go away!
うっせーな　あっち行け
If you try anything weird, I'll throw you out.
っつかお前　あんまり非常識のことすると追い出すぞ
I could've done it myself.
手伝ってくれなくても大丈夫なのに
春君お客様なんだから
Shun-kun, you're a guest.
日紗子ちゃんだってそうじゃないですか
So are you, Hisako-chan.
私は昔からよく出入りしてたしさ
I've spent lots of time here since I was little.
今更って感じ
And now, after all these years...
Oh, his medicine.
あ　薬
要君お昼の分ちゃんと飲んだのかな
Did Kaname-kun take any this afternoon?
持って行ったほうがいいかな
Should we take it to him?
You worry too much!
もう　気回しすぎよ
要君って
Kaname-kun...
He's never relied on others.
昔から全然周りに頼ることとかないですよね
Tsukahara Kaname
3 days, 3 times a day
Dosage: 1 capsule
Instructions: Please take within 30 minutes of every meal
Coldcurin 250
僕なんかいつも助けてもらってるのに
He's always helping me with things,
助けてあげることなんてほとんど
but I never get to help him.
Oh, right.
Yeah.
Well, that's fine, isn't it?
まあ　いいんじゃない
Huh?
え　いいのかな
You think so?
I'm sure he doesn't mind.
要はそれでいいのよ
Chizuru's Ultra Dive!
千鶴選手のultra dive
満点　満点です　千鶴選手　満点
A perfect score! He's done it!
You scored a zero!
He's set a new world record!
零点だ　頭が　っていうか　退け　サル
That hurts. Get off, you monkey!
世界新記録
ちょっと　今なんか　すごい音が
What's all that noise?
Chizuru-kun, don't do that.
千鶴君　ダメですよ　要君は風邪を引い
Kaname-kun is sick...
Huh? What?
え　あのう
Hey. If you don't stop, you'll...
ちょっと　いい加減にしないと床が
So heavy... You're all so heavy.
重い　重いよ　君たち
I hit my chin.
あご振った
Shun's jump was too low.
春のジャンプが低かったから
え　僕のせいじゃ
It wasn't my fault.
You did this to yourselves!
自業自得だろう
退け　早く退け　早く
Sorry about today.
今日はごめんなさい
お見舞いっていうか　さらに悪化させただけみたいな
We came to visit you,
but all we did was make things worse.
You really did.
本当にな
Take it easy tomorrow.
明日はゆっくり休んでください
何　要チ明日も休むわけ
You're taking tomorrow off, too?
How does that negatively affect you?
休んでお前らに不都合あるのかよ
いいや　むしろ要チがいない
Actually, it'll be great going to school without you yelling at me.
今日の学校生活はどなれなくて快適でございました
Huh?
でも　何日もいないと飽きるから　やっぱ早く来てよ
But it'll get boring without you, so get well soon.
それじゃ　要君　お大事に
Take care, Kaname-kun.
Byebye
Bye bye.
You heard them.
だってさ
だってさじゃねえよ
Don't give me that.
だったら見舞いに来て騒ぐなっつうの
They shouldn't have made such a racket when they visited.
But I think you're looking a little better.
でもあんた顔色ちょっとよくなったんじゃない
Your fever's down.
熱下がったよ　騒いで汗かいたから
All that racket made you sweat it off.
Shut up.
うるせい
The rainy days continue.
雨の日はまだまだ続く
梅雨は嫌いだ　でも雨は嫌いじゃない
I hate the rainy season.
I don't hate the rain, though.
窓を打つ雨の音は騒がしく
The rain pounds noisily on my window,
but there's something comforting about the sound.
けれどどこか心地よい
Hisako.
日紗子
There are notebooks on my desk. Can you bring them to me?
机の上にノートあるから
取ってくれよ
What?
If I'm going to lie here, I might as well look over my notes from class.
どうせ寝てるなら　授業の見直しでもしてる方が有意義だろう
Actually,
や　そうじゃなくて　ノートなら先あの子たちが全部持ってたけど
those boys just left with all of your notebooks.
What?
Classics
うほ　完璧じゃん
His notes are perfect!
Classics
They really are.
そうですね
Classics
何しに来たんだ　あいつら
What did they come here for, exactly?!
僕は泣き虫で　悔しくて
boku wa nakimushi de kuyashikute dakedo
It pains me to be such a crybaby,
だけどあなたに今伝えたいんだ
anata ni ima tsutaetai n da
but I want to tell you my feelings right now
tada massugu ni boku wo mitsumeru tsuyokute
There you stand, silently gazing at me
ただまっすぐに僕を見つめる
強くて優しいその瞳に応えるために
yasashii sono hitomi ni kotaeru tame ni
Giving me the chance to answer you and the strength and tenderness in your eyes
itsushika miushinatteta ichiban taisetsu na mono mo
you taught me about what I lost sight of
いつしか見失ってた
一番大切なものも
sotto anata ga oshiete kureta
that was most important to me
そっとあなたが教えてくれた
tashika ni sou omoeru kara
I have no doubts about that
たしかにそう思えるから
boku wa yowamushi de iya datta n dakedo
I hated how weak I was
僕は弱虫で　嫌だった
だけどもっともっと強くなるから
motto motto tsuyoku naru kara
but I will continue to become stronger
anata no koto mo mamoreru you na boku ni naru kara
I will be someone who could protect you and me both
あなたのことを守れるような僕になるから
dakara sukoshi mattete
so wait a little longer for me
だから　少し待ってて
Next time: One Summer
One Summer